Trump-threatening military intervention of Nigeria is really about access to Niger,
Burkina Faso, and Mali, the alliance of Sahel states. This is going to be an intervention
on behalf of France. Ever since Niger nationalized its uranium assets, the same uranium that France
was using, stealing, to run its nuclear reactors, to make itself a nuclear power, a superpower,
Niger is asserting its own sovereignty over its natural resources, same as Burkina Faso,
same as Mali with its gold, Burkina Faso with its gold, and other resources. So this is making
NATO very nervous. Countries like Ivory Coast have expelled French troops from their country,
Chad as well. Also, Senegal as well kicked out French troops. Remember, West Africa is where France gets
all of its power from. Without total domination, subjugation, and sabotage of West African states,
France has absolutely no power. It is toothless. Right now, 14 West and Central African countries
use something called the CFA franc. It is a currency that is backed, that is attached to the French franc
at first, and now the euro. These 14 countries are required to pay half of their foreign exchange
reserves paid back into the French treasury. And if these countries say no, also remember that Abuja
in Nigeria is the seat of ECOWAS, the Economic Community of West African States. This is an
regional economic bloc that seeks to put all of these West African states under the control of the
African Union and, by extension, the European Union. That is why you will find that the people of Nigeria
are the very last to benefit from the resources of Nigeria because of economic blocs that do not
favor the prosperity of African people like ECOWAS. And so, Bola Tinubu, the president of Nigeria,
is very disgruntled that the alliance of Sahel states of Niger, Mali, and Burkina Faso want to exit ECOWAS,
have actually exited from ECOWAS. They do not want to be under the yoke of imperialism any longer.
So, this is all about France losing its grip and viability as a world superpower. So, America wants
to intervene on its behalf.